<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas-r5/fhir-single.xsd">
	<p>This section lists the use cases for order catalogs, sorted by category of catalog.</p>
	<a name="labservice"> </a>
	<h3>Laboratory services compendium</h3>
	<ul>
		<li>A clinical or pathology laboratory wishes to share its full compendium of diagnostic
			services with the healthcare professionals and organizations wishing to use these
			diagnostic services. It publishes it as a catalog of resources accessible online for
			discovery and retrieval. Consumers query the catalog online from their order entry
			application and retrieve the diagnostic services they want to insert into their order to
			the laboratory for their patient. </li>
		<li> Variant 1: A consumer imports periodically the subset of the catalog it is interested
			in, so as to have it available locally for its computerizedd physician order entry
			application.</li>
		<li> Variant 2: The laboratory maintains its compendium of services in a proprietary format,
			and delegates the standard publication of this compendium to an external organization
			operating an HL7 FHIR server of such catalogs. The application maintaining the
			laboratory compendium interacts with the FHIR server to keep the publication up to date,
			inserting, updating or retiring services into/from the FHIR catalog. </li>
	</ul>
	<br/>
	<a name="orderset"> </a>
	<h3>Order sets library</h3>
	<ul>
		<li>A client of a content vendor’s system wishes to import the latest set of published order
			sets into its own catalog for deployment into its EHR.</li>
		<li>A content vendor wishes to import a collection of order sets from one of its client
			including all dependencies (e.g., orderable items mentioned in the order sets, order
			details, relevant order item constraints, etc…) into its own catalog.</li>
		<li/>
		<li>A health care provider wishes to sync its orderable item catalog and order set library
			with a content vendor. Any term added, updated, or inactivated should reflect
			immediately on the content vendor side. Also, the health care provider wishes to
			identify any catalog item that references an inactivated orderable item on the content
			vendor system in order to update the order set. </li>
		<li>A medication has been recalled. A content provider and a health care provider would like
			to identify all order sets that reference this recalled medication. The health care
			provider then wishes to sync its order set library with that of the content vendor’s and
			update all affected order sets based on vendor guidance prior to reimporting the updated
			order sets back into their own catalog. The updated order sets, are then deployed into
			the EHR.</li>
		<li>A health care organization with multiple facilities and hospitals maintains a master
			catalog of order sets. Each facility maintains its library of order sets and vocabulary
			derived from the master catalog but localized based on the facility’s needs and
			capabilities. Updates to the master catalog should be reflected at the individual
			facility/hospital level based on the governance practices of the facility and the parent
			organization.</li>
		<li>The client of a content vendor would like to import order sets ready for publication
			into their system. They search the catalog for all active order sets that are ready for
			publication and import that set into their local catalog. Once imported, an integrator
			reviews the order sets, makes the necessary changes, and deploys them to the EHR.</li>
	</ul>
	<br/>
	<a name="drug"> </a>
	<h3>Catalog of medications</h3>
	<ul>
		<li>A health care organization maintains its medication formulary and shares it to the
			applications used by its physicians, nurses and pharmacists to support medication
			prescription, dispense and administration.</li>
		<li>A content vendor publishes the general catalog of medications authorized to a national
			market. Health care organizations of the country import subsets of this general catalog
			so as to synchronize their local medication formularies. </li>
		<li>Variant 1: In addition to the general catalog of medications, the content vendor hosts
			the medication formularies of each of its client organizations who interact with the
			server to use their own medication formulary in their medication workflows, as well as
			to maintain this mefication formularty over time (inserting/updating/retiring items.
		</li>
	</ul>
	<br/>
	<h3>Catalog of medical devices</h3>
	<ul>
		<li>LIVD. Link to LIVD IG.</li>
		<li>A content vendor publishes the general catalog of medical devices authorized to a
			national market. Health care organizations of the country access this catalog in real
			time during their health care processes using medical devices, so as to retrieve all the
			details of the devices, and to trace their association to patients. </li>
	</ul>
	<p>
		<img src="anImage.png" alt="A sample image" width="200px"/>
	</p>
</div>
