<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas-r5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <!-- The spaces between the open and close "a" tag are mandatory.  (Cuz HTML renderers are dumb...) -->
  <a name="intro"> </a>
  <h3>Introduction</h3>
  <p> An order catalog exposes a homogeneous collection of healthcare items that can be ordered or
    selected by practitioners during the course of care delivery. These homogeneous healthcare items
    may represent services, products, devices or knowledge artefacts. Each item specifies its
    purpose, describes how it should be ordered and/or used, and characterizes the outcomes that one
    can expect from this usage. </p>
  <p> Examples include order sets catalog, evidence based CDS content, laboratory test compendium,
    medication formulary, catalog of medical devices. Order catalogs have varied scopes, sizes,
    ownerships and targetted consumers and jurisdictions. For instance an order catalog might expose
    the medical devices of a particular manufacturer to the potential users of these devices in a
    country. Another catalog might consolidate all the medical devices that are approved for use in
    healthcare throughout the Europe Union market. Another example of order catalog would be a drug
    formulary listing the medicinal products that are available for prescription in a particular
    hospital. A broader catalog of medicinal product might include all the medications authorized to
    the national market of a country. </p>
  <a name="technical"> </a>
  <h3>Technical Overview</h3>
  <p> Additional detail/context setting for those who have significant background in the domain.
    (Try to make as understandable as you can, but set important context). </p>
  <a name="walkthrough"> </a>
  <p> The main sections of this IG are: </p>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="background.html">Background</a> - provides business context for the implementation
      guide and information that implementers should be familiar with before reading the remainder
      of the IG. There could be multiple pages for this. </li>
    <li>
      <a href="spec.html">Detailed Specification</a> - The actual stuff implementers are expected to
      do. (Could be multiple pages for this.) </li>
    <li>
      <a href="downloads.html">Downloads</a> - Allows downloading a copy of this implementation
      guide and other useful information </li>
  </ul>
</div>
