<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas-r5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <!-- The spaces between the open and close "a" tag are mandatory.  (Cuz HTML renderers are dumb...) -->
  <a name="intro"> </a>
  <h3>Introduction to this implementation guide</h3>
  <p>This implementation guide for sharing order catalogs is targetting FHIR R4 and the universal realm.</p>
  <p> An order catalog exposes a homogeneous collection of healthcare items that can be ordered or
    selected by practitioners to support the course of healthcare delivery. These homogeneous
    healthcare items may represent services, products, devices or knowledge artifacts such as order
    sets, for instance. Each item specifies its purpose, describes how it should be ordered and/or
    used, and characterizes the outcomes that one can expect from its usage. </p>
  <p> Examples of catalogs include order sets catalog, evidence based CDS content, laboratory test
    compendium, medication formulary, catalog of medical devices. </p>
  <p> This universal realm implementation guide specifies the methods and artifacts based on the
    FHIR standard, to enable the sharing of catalogs of healthcare items across practitioners and
    organizations. The methods such as browsing, searching, retrieval, or maintaining the content,
    are common regarless of the catagory of catalog at hand: product, service, clinical knowledge...
    Some of the artifacts, like the one representing the catalog as a whole, are also common to all
    categories of catalogs. Other artifacts are specific to the category of items (medication,
    device, order set, diagnostic service ...) exposed by the catalog. </p>
  <p>Considering these commonalities and specificities, building a common guidance for implementing
    any kind of catalog of healthcare items in FHIR has been deemed the most valuable proposition to
    implementers. Hence this unique Order Catalog Implementation Guide, which aims to cover all
    categories of catalogs of healthcare items. The use cases and artifacts (profiles, extensions, semantic
    resources) that are specific to a particular category of catalog will be placed under the
    responsibility of the HL7 Working Group defining the base resources for this category. </p>
  <a name="purpose"> </a>
  <h3>Purpose of order catalogs</h3>
  <p> A catalog provides reference data, which aggregates requirements and guidance of usage for the
    items of the catalog, from multiple sources: regulatory, clinical knowledge, organizational
    (based on the organization of the provider of the items). These reference data are assembled
    under the stewardship of the catalog custodian: an organization liable for building and sharing
    the catalog, and maintaining it over time.</p>
  <p>Catalogs are hosted on servers which make them accessible to the practitioners through their IT
    systems or applications (e.g. EHR, EMR, CPOE, apps, LIS, Pharmacy system ...) Client
    applications may interact with a catalog server to: </p>
  <ul>
    <li>browse through entries of the catalog and retrieve items of interest together with the
      detailed instructions and guidance related to the usage of these items,</li>
    <li>import/export the full catalog or a part of it (e.g. import the recent updates), </li>
    <li>administer the content of the catalog: add/update/retire items and/or supporting resources.
    </li>
  </ul>
  <br/>
  <a name="scope"> </a>
  <h3>Scope of order catalogs</h3>
  <p> Order catalogs have varied scopes, sizes, ownerships and targetted consumers and
    jurisdictions. For instance an order catalog might expose the medical devices of a particular
    manufacturer to the potential users of these devices in a country. Another catalog might
    consolidate all the medical devices that are approved for use in healthcare throughout the
    European Union market. Another example of order catalog would be a drug formulary listing the
    medicinal products that are available for prescription in a particular hospital. A broader
    catalog of medicinal product might include all the medications authorized to the national market
    of a country. These examples illustrate that:</p>
  <ul>
    <li>the role of custodian of the catalog is distinct from the role of owner of the items
      exposed in the catalog, even if in one of the examples above the two roles may be played by
      the same organization;</li>
    <li>some catalogs may expose a huge number of items, and yet the FHIR resources that implement
      them must stay of manageable size;</li>
    <li>some catalogs are scoped for use within a single organization, while others address multiple
      organizations (or even jurisdictions) of potential consumers.</li>
  </ul>
  <br/>
  <a name="technical"> </a>
  <h3>Technical Overview</h3>
  <p> In the FHIR standard, an order catalog as a whole is represented by an instance of the
    Composition resource, which conveys the general properties of the catalog (e.g. owner, title,
    period of validity, type of content), and each item of the catalog is represented by a
    definitional resource, possibly associated with a set of supporting resources providing further
    details on this item. Two alternative methods are usable to bind the catalog as a whole to its
    items. </p>
  <ol>
    <li>The catalog references its items from its Composition.section.entry elements. This method
      constrains the Composition resource with the Catalog profile.</li>
    <li>Each definitional resource representing an item references the Composition resource. The
      Composition resource in this case acts as the header of the catalog. This method constrains
      the Composition resource with the CatalogHeader profile. </li>
  </ol>
  <img src="CatalogBindings.png" alt="Methods for binding catalogs and their items" width="600px"/>
  <p> The catalog server must choose one of the two methods, and cannot mix the two methods for one
    catalog. Usable for catalogs of any size, the second method is in particular more appropriate
    for large catalogs because it makes the administration of the content easier. In particular,
    adding a new item or retiring an item does not impose any update to the Composition resource
    representing the catalog as a whole.</p>
  <a name="walkthrough"> </a>
  <h3>Walkthrough</h3>
  <p> The main sections of this IG are: </p>
  <ul>
    <li title="Use cases"><strong>Use cases</strong>
      <ul>
        <li><a href="uclabservices.html">Laboratory services</a> - lists the use cases for compendium of laboratory diagnostic services. </li>
        <li><a href="ucordersets.html">Order sets</a> - lists the use cases for library of order sets. </li>
        <li><a href="ucdrugs.html">Medications</a> - lists the use cases for catalog of drugs. </li>
        <li><a href="ucdevices.html">Devices</a> - lists the use cases for catalog of devices. </li>
      </ul>
    </li>
    <li title="Specifications"><strong>Specifications</strong>
      <ul>
        <li><a href="labservices.html">Laboratory services</a> - specifies the FHIR resources implemented by a compendium of laboratory diagnostic services. </li>
        <li><a href="ordersets.html">Order sets</a> - specifies the FHIR resources implemented by a library of order sets. </li>
        <li><a href="drugs.html">Medications</a> - specifies the FHIR resources implemented by a catalog of drugs, including medication formularies. </li>
        <li><a href="devices.html">Devices</a> - specifies the FHIR resources implemented by a catalog of devices. </li>
      </ul>
    </li>
    <li title="Examples"><strong>Examples</strong>
      <ul>
        <li><a href="exlabservices.html">Laboratory services</a> - presents examples for compendia of laboratory diagnostic services. </li>
        <li><a href="exordersets.html">Order sets</a> - presents examples for libraries of order sets. </li>
        <li><a href="exdrugs.html">Medications</a> - presents examples for catalogs of drugs. </li>
        <li><a href="exdevices.html">Devices</a> - presents examples for catalogs of devices. </li>
      </ul>
    </li>
    <li title="Examples"><strong>Building blocks &amp; assets</strong>
      <ul>
        <li><a href="artifacts.html">Artifact Index</a> - provides all the detailed artifacts built for this implementation guide: semantic resources, profiles, extensions, examples. </li>
        <li><a href="downloads.html">Downloads</a> - Allows downloading a copy of this implementation guide and other useful information. </li>
      </ul>
    </li>
  </ul>
  <br/>
  <a name="authors"> </a>
  <h3>Authors and Contributors</h3>
  <table>
    <thead>
      <tr>
        <th>Role</th>
        <th>Name</th>
        <th>Organization</th>
      </tr>
    </thead>
    <tbody>
      <tr>
        <td>Publishing Facilitator</td>
        <td>Rob Hausam</td>
        <td>Hausam Consulting LLC</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>Primary Editor</td>
        <td>François Macary</td>
        <td>Phast</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>Contributor</td>
        <td>Freida Hall</td>
        <td>Quest Diagnostics</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>Contributor</td>
        <td>Gary Randman</td>
        <td>Quest Diagnostics</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>Contributor</td>
        <td>Kathy Walsh</td>
        <td>LabCorp</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>Contributor</td>
        <td>Andrea Pitkus</td>
        <td>U of Wisconsin</td>
      </tr>
    </tbody>
  </table>
</div>
