<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas-r5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <!-- The spaces between the open and close "a" tag are mandatory.  (Cuz HTML renderers are dumb...) -->
  <table class="note-to-balloters">
    <tbody>
      <tr>
        <th>The scope of next ballot includes catalogs of laboratory services, medications and devices. <br/>
		Pages which are excluded from this ballot will be signaled as such by
          a note to balloters at the top of the page. <br/>Feedback is welcome and may be submitted
          through the <a href="http://hl7.org/fhir-issues"> FHIR Jira tracker</a></th>
      </tr>
    </tbody>
  </table>
  <br/>
  <a name="intro"> </a>
  <h3>Introduction to this guide</h3>
  <p>This implementation guide for sharing order catalogs is based on FHIR R5. Its scope is
    international (aka universal realm).</p>
  <p> An order catalog is a collection of definitional resources describing homogeneous healthcare items that can be
    ordered, selected or used by practitioners to support the course of healthcare delivery. These
    homogeneous healthcare items may represent services, products, devices or knowledge artifacts
    (e.g., order sets). Each item specifies its purpose, describes how it should be
    ordered and/or used, and characterizes the outcomes expected from its usage. </p>
  <p> Examples of catalogs include order sets catalog, evidence based knowledge artifacts for
    clinical decision support (CDS), laboratory test compendium, medication formulary, catalog of
    medical devices. </p>
  <p> This universal realm implementation guide specifies the methods and artifacts based on the
    FHIR standard, to build catalogs of healthcare items and share the content of these catalogs
    across practitioners and healthcare organizations. The methods such as browse, search,
    retrieve, or maintain the content, are common regardless of the category of catalog at hand:
    product, service, clinical knowledge. Some of the artifacts, like the one representing the
    catalog as a whole, are also common to all categories of catalogs. Other artifacts are specific
    to a category of items (medication, device, order set, diagnostic service ...) exposed by the
    catalog. </p>
  <p>Considering these commonalities and specificities, building a common guidance for implementing
    any kind of catalog of healthcare items in FHIR has been deemed the most valuable proposition to
    implementers. Hence this unique Order Catalog Implementation Guide, which aims to cover all
    categories of catalogs of healthcare items. The use cases and artifacts (profiles, extensions,
    semantic resources) that are specific to a particular category of catalog will be placed under
    the responsibility of the HL7 Working Group maintaining the base resources for this category. </p>
  <a name="walkthrough"> </a>
  <h3>How to read this Guide</h3>
  <p> This Guide is organized in a number of pages accessible from the top menu bar.</p>
  <ul>
    <li title="Home"><a href="index.html"><strong>Home:</strong></a> This home page provides the <a
        href="index.html#intro">introduction</a>, <a href="index.html#sponsoringwg"
          >background</a> and <a href="index.html#authors">contributors</a> to this Guide, stresses its purpose and scope as well as the roles
      interacting on catalogs. It also provides the <a href="index.html#technical">general technical
        design</a> for implementing catalogs of healthcare items in the FHIR standard.</li>
    <li title="Use cases"><strong>Use cases</strong>: The pages under this menu option present the
      use cases covered by the Guide, organized per kind of catalog: <ul>
        <li><a href="uclabservices.html">Laboratory services</a> - lists the use cases for
          compendium of laboratory diagnostic services. </li>
        <li><a href="ucordersets.html">Order sets</a> - lists the use cases for library of order
          sets. </li>
        <li><a href="ucdrugs.html">Medications</a> - lists the use cases for catalog of drugs. </li>
        <li><a href="ucdevices.html">Devices</a> - lists the use cases for catalog of devices. </li>
      </ul>
    </li>
    <li title="Specifications"><strong>Specifications</strong>: The pages under this menu option
      provide the functional specifications, organized per kind of catalog: <ul>
        <li><a href="labservices.html">Laboratory services</a> - specifies the FHIR resources
          implemented by a compendium of laboratory diagnostic services. </li>
        <li><a href="ordersets.html">Order sets</a> - specifies the FHIR resources implemented by a
          library of order sets. </li>
        <li><a href="drugs.html">Medications</a> - specifies the FHIR resources implemented by a
          catalog of drugs, including medication formularies. </li>
        <li><a href="devices.html">Devices</a> - specifies the FHIR resources implemented by a
          catalog of devices. </li>
      </ul>
    </li>
    <li title="Interactions"><a href="interactions.html"><strong>Interaction Framework</strong></a>:
      The page under this menu option specifies the interaction framework applicable to all kinds of
      catalogs.</li>
    <li title="Examples"><strong>Examples</strong>: The pages under this menu option present
      examples of catalog healthcare items. They are organized per kind of catalog: <ul>
        <li><a href="exlabservices.html">Laboratory services</a> - presents examples for compendia
          of laboratory diagnostic services. </li>
        <li><a href="exordersets.html">Order sets</a> - presents examples for libraries of order
          sets. </li>
        <li><a href="exdrugs.html">Medications</a> - presents examples for catalogs of drugs. </li>
        <li><a href="exdevices.html">Devices</a> - presents examples for catalogs of medical devices. </li>
      </ul>
    </li>
    <li title="Artifacts"><a href="artifacts.html"><strong>Artifact Index</strong></a>: The page
      under this menu option presents the standardized artifacts built for this Guide: <ul>
        <li><a href="artifacts.html#1">Profiles</a></li>
        <li><a href="artifacts.html#2">Extension definitions</a></li>
        <li><a href="artifacts.html#3">Value sets</a></li>
        <li><a href="artifacts.html#4">Code systems</a></li>
        <li><a href="artifacts.html#5">Example instances</a></li>
      </ul>
    </li>
    <li title="Downloads"><a href="downloads.html"><strong>Downloads</strong></a>: The page under
      this menu option allows to download a copy of the artifacts and other useful information of
      this implementation guide. </li>
  </ul>
  <a name="sponsoringwg"> </a>
  <h3>Project and sponsoring background</h3>
  <p>This IG is one of the product deliverables of project <a
      href="http://www.hl7.org/special/Committees/projman/searchableProjectIndex.cfm?action=edit&amp;ProjectNumber=1010"
      >Ordering Service Interface Specification Project <b>#1010</b></a>, which is sponsored by
    Orders &amp; Observations WG, and co-sponsored by Clinical Decision Support WG, Pharmacy WG,
    Imaging Integration WG and Service Oriented Architecture WG. The intention is that each work
    group contributes on its domain of expertise, to this cross-domain FHIR IG.</p>
  <a name="purpose"> </a>
  <h3>Purpose of order catalogs</h3>
  <p> A catalog holds master data providing the definitions of healthcare items. It may include,
    where applicable, the associated regulatory constraints, business requirements and clinical
    guidelines for ordering and using these items.</p>
  <p>Catalogs are most often stored on servers which make them accessible to practitioners
    through their IT systems or applications e.g., electronic health records, electronic medical
    records, computerized physcian order entry, laboratory information systems, medication dispense
    systems... Client applications interact with the FHIR API of a catalog server to: </p>
  <ul>
    <li>browse through entries of the catalog and retrieve items of interest together with the
      detailed instructions and guidance related to the usage of these items,</li>
    <li>import the full catalog or a part of it (e.g., recently updated items, a subset of the
      catalog dedicated to a specialty, ...), </li>
    <li>administer the content of the catalog if authorized to do so; add, update, retire items and supporting resources.
    </li>
  </ul>
  <p>In addition, catalogs may also be exported in part or in whole to the consumer's system, using the FHIR
    messaging framework</p>
  <a name="scope"> </a>
  <h3>Scopes of order catalogs and roles involved</h3>
  <p> Order catalogs have varied scopes, sizes, ownerships, stewardships and targeted consumers and
    jurisdictions. For instance an order catalog might expose the medical devices of a particular
    manufacturer to the potential users of these devices in a country. Another catalog might
    consolidate all the medical devices that are approved for use in healthcare throughout the
    European Union market. Another example of order catalog would be a drug formulary listing the
    medicinal products that are available for prescription in a particular hospital. A broader
    catalog of medicinal product might include all the medications authorized to the national market
    of a country. These examples illustrate various scopes and sizes of catalogs:</p>
  <ul>
    <li>some catalogs may expose a huge number of items, and yet the FHIR resources that implement
      them must have a reasonable size, which does not hamper the management (creation, update,
      query, retrieval) of these resources ;</li>
    <li>some catalogs are scoped for use within a single organization, while others address multiple
      organizations (or even jurisdictions) of potential consumers.</li>
  </ul>
  <p>These examples also illustrate these roles involved in catalog interactions:</p>
  <ul>
    <li><b>Catalog consumer</b>: A system using the content of the catalog in its own local
      operations in healthcare (e.g. order entry of health products or services, or application of
      knowledge artifacts).</li>
    <li><b>Catalog custodian</b>: A system maintaining over time the catalog as a shareable object
      accessible by consumers through a FHIR interface.</li>
    <li><b>Catalog owner</b>: A system owning the content of the catalog.</li>
  </ul>
  <p>The roles of custodian and owner may belong to a single organization and in that case, be
    combined in a single system. Conversely, for some of the examples above these roles may be
    played by two distinct organizations, each with its own system, in which case, FHIR interactions
    are needed between these two roles to administer the content of the shared catalog. </p>
  <p>The interactions between those three roles are described in the <a href="interactions.html"
      >Interaction Framework</a> of this guide.</p>
  <a name="outofscope"> </a>
  <h3>Out of Scope</h3>
  <ul>
    <li>A catalog conformant to this IG does not contain any personal health data, and therefore
      presents no risk of privacy breach. Thus, ensuring privacy by design is out of scope of this
      IG.</li>
    <li>A catalog conforming to this guide is a collection of definitional resources, originated by
      a single actor: the catalog owner, and shared on the FHIR API by a single actor - the catalog
      custodian. There is no need to trace and reconcile update activities of multiple actors on any
      of the resources of the catalog. Data provenance is therefore known a priori. This is why
      handling data provenance with the Provenance resource is out of scope of this IG.</li>
    <li>Definitional resources describing an orderable item of the catalog guide the generation of
      orders of this item, as well as reports fulfilling these orders. The exact methods for
      generating the workflow resources from the definitional resources depend on the standard
      chosen (HL7 v2, FHIR) to convey the workflow objects (orders, tasks, reports ...). The
      definition of these methods is currently beyond the scope of this IG.</li>
  </ul>
  <a name="technical"> </a>
  <h3>Technical Overview</h3>
  <p> In the FHIR standard, an order catalog as a whole is represented by an instance of the
    Composition resource, which conveys the general properties of the catalog (e.g. custodian,
    title, period of validity, type of content), and each item of the catalog is represented by a
    definitional resource, possibly associated with a set of supporting resources providing further
    details on this item. Two alternative methods are usable to bind the catalog as a whole to its
    items. </p>
  <ol>
    <li>The catalog references its items from its Composition.section.entry elements. This method
      constrains the Composition resource with the <a
        href="http://hl7.org/fhir/composition-catalog.html">Catalog profile</a>, which is part of
      the base standard.</li>
    <li>Each definitional resource representing an item references the Composition resource. The
      Composition resource in this case acts as the header of the catalog. This method constrains
      the Composition resource with the CatalogHeader profile. </li>
  </ol>
  <img src="CatalogBindings.png" alt="Methods for binding catalogs and their items" width="600px"/>
  <p> The catalog custodian may support both methods. It is recommended to choose one method for a
    catalog instance. Usable for catalogs of any size, the second method is more appropriate for
    large catalogs because it makes the administration of the content easier. In particular, adding
    a new item or retiring an item does not impose any update to the Catalog or the CatalogHeader
    resource representing the catalog as a whole.</p>
  <a name="authors"> </a>
  <h3>Authors and Contributors</h3>
  <table>
    <thead>
      <tr>
        <th>Role</th>
        <th>Name</th>
        <th>Organization</th>
      </tr>
    </thead>
    <tbody>
      <tr>
        <td>Primary Editor</td>
        <td>François Macary</td>
        <td>Phast</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>Primary Editor</td>
        <td>Rob Hausam</td>
        <td>Hausam Consulting LLC</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>Contributor</td>
        <td>Freida Hall</td>
        <td>Quest Diagnostics</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>Contributor</td>
        <td>Gary Randman</td>
        <td>Quest Diagnostics</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>Contributor</td>
        <td>Kathy Walsh</td>
        <td>LabCorp</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>Contributor</td>
        <td>Andrea Pitkus</td>
        <td>U of Wisconsin</td>
      </tr>
    </tbody>
  </table>
</div>
