<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas-r5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <!-- The spaces between the open and close "a" tag are mandatory.  (Cuz HTML renderers are dumb...) -->
  <a name="intro"> </a>
  <h3>Introduction</h3>
  <p> An order catalog exposes a homogeneous collection of healthcare items that can be ordered or
    selected by practitioners during the course of care delivery. These homogeneous healthcare items
    may represent services, products, devices or knowledge artifacts. Each item specifies its
    purpose, describes how it should be ordered and/or used, and characterizes the outcomes that one
    can expect from this usage. </p>
  <p> Examples include order sets catalog, evidence based CDS content, laboratory test compendium,
    medication formulary, catalog of medical devices. Order catalogs have varied scopes, sizes,
    ownerships and targetted consumers and jurisdictions. For instance an order catalog might expose
    the medical devices of a particular manufacturer to the potential users of these devices in a
    country. Another catalog might consolidate all the medical devices that are approved for use in
    healthcare throughout the Europe Union market. Another example of order catalog would be a drug
    formulary listing the medicinal products that are available for prescription in a particular
    hospital. A broader catalog of medicinal product might include all the medications authorized to
    the national market of a country. </p>
  <p> A catalog provides reference data, which aggregates requirements of usage for the items of the
    catalog, from multiple sources: regulatory, clinical knowledge, organizational (based on the
    organization of the provider of the items). </p>
  <p>Catalogs are meant to be used by IT systems and applications (e.g. EHR, EMR, CPOE, apps, LIS,
    Pharmacy system ...) as well as by humans. Humans interact with catalogs through the mediation
    of their applications. Client applications may interact with a catalog to: </p>
  <ul>
    <li>browse through entries of the catalog and retrieve items of interest together with the
      detailed instructions and guidance related to the usage of these items,</li>
    <li>import/export the full catalog or a part of it (e.g. import the recent updates), </li>
    <li>administer the content of the catalog: add/update/retire items and/or supporting resources.
    </li>
  </ul>
  <a name="technical"> </a>
  <h3>Technical Overview</h3>
  <p> In the FHIR standard, an order catalog as a whole is represented by an instance of the
    Composition resource, which conveys the general properties of the catalog (e.g. owner, title,
    period of validity, type of content), and each item of the catalog is represented by a
    definitional resource, possibly associated with a set of supporting resources providing further
    details on this item. Two alternative methods are usable to bind the catalog as a whole to its
    items. </p>
  <ol>
    <li>The catalog references its items from its Composition.section.entry elements. This method
      constrains the Composition resource with the Catalog profile.</li>
    <li>Each definitional resource representing an item references the Composition resource. The
      Composition resource in this case acts as the header of the catalog. This method constrains
      the Composition resource with the CatalogHeader profile. </li>
  </ol>
  <img src="CatalogBindings.png" alt="Methods for binding catalogs and their items" width="700px"/>
  <p> The catalog owner must choose one of the two methods, and cannot mix the two methods for one
    catalog. Usable for catalogs of any size, the second method is in particular more appropriate
    for large catalogs because it makes the administration of the content easier. In particular,
    adding a new item or retiring an item does not impose any update to the Composition resource
    representing the catalog as a whole.</p>
  <a name="walkthrough"> </a>
  <h3>Walkthrough</h3>
  <p> The main sections of this IG are: </p>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="background.html">Background</a> - provides business context for the implementation
      guide and information that implementers should be familiar with before reading the remainder
      of the IG. There could be multiple pages for this. </li>
    <li>
      <a href="spec.html">Detailed Specification</a> - The actual stuff implementers are expected to
      do. (Could be multiple pages for this.) </li>
    <li>
      <a href="downloads.html">Downloads</a> - Allows downloading a copy of this implementation
      guide and other useful information </li>
  </ul>
</div>
