<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas-r5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <p>This page provides the detailed specifications for catalogs of laboratory diagnostic
    services.</p>
  <h3>Resources and Profiles</h3>
  <p>The figure below shows the resources and profiles used to represent catalogs of laboratory
    diagnostic services</p>
  <img src="LabCompendium.png" alt="Resources used by a laboratory service compendium" width="800px"/>
  <p>Catalogs of laboratory services use exclusively the <a
      href="StructureDefinition-CatalogHeader.html"> CatalogHeader profile</a> for the resource
    Composition. In other words, for binding a laboratory catalog to its items, only method 2 is
    usable, as depicted in <a href="index.html#technical"> Home Page - Technical overview</a> .
    Thus, the Composition resource holds only the general properties of the catalog and is
    referenced by the resources PlanDefinition constrained by the <a href="StructureDefinition-LabServiceDefinition.html"> LabServiceDefinition</a> profile, which represent the
    items of the catalog. </p>
  <p>An item of the catalog is a laboratory service instantiated as a PlanDefinition, which
    represents either a test (type=test) or a panel (type=panel). A panel is a set of tests and/or
    panels. This PlanDefinition conveys the general properties of the item (identification, names
    and codings, orderability, applicability, jurisdictions, billing, status, possible replacement
    by another more recent item, gender or species restrictions ...). The PlanDefinition contains a
    single occurrence of the element PlanDefinition.action. </p>
  <p>The PlanDefinition.action references one or more instances of ActivityDefinition constrained by
    the <a href="StructureDefinition-LabProcedureDefinition.html">LabProcedureDefinition profile, </a> each of which represents a laboratory procedure with its
    operational details, specifying in particular the specimens required to perform the test or
    panel, the input observations expected by the laboratory from the orderer, and the output
    observations that the procedure will produce.</p>
  <p>In most cases the PlanDefinition references a single ActivityDefinition, which represents the
    operational view of the service.</p>
  <p>In some cases the PlanDefinition of a lab service references multiple instances of
    ActivityDefinition representing multiple procedures assembled in logical groups with
    combinations of AND and OR. These logical combinations are used for example to indicate that the
    laboratory accepts multiple alternative specimens (e.g. venous blood versus capillary blood) to
    perform a test.</p>
</div>
