<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas-r5/fhir-single.xsd">
	<p>This section lists the use cases for using catalogs of laboratory diagnostic services.</p>
	<ol>
		<li><b>Laboratory catalog shared in pull mode</b>: A clinical or pathology laboratory wishes
			to share its full compendium of diagnostic services with the healthcare professionals
			and organizations wishing to use these diagnostic services. It publishes it as a catalog
			of resources accessible online for discovery and retrieval. Consumers query the catalog
			online from their order entry application and retrieve the diagnostic services they want
			to insert into their orders to the laboratory for their patients. Implementation
			guidance for this use case is provided in the <a
				href="labservices.html#LabServicesSearchRetrieve"><i>Searching and retrieving
					laboratory services</i></a> section of the specification.</li>
		<li>
			<b>Subset of catalog imported by consumer</b>: A consumer selects a subset of interest
			for its local need from the online laboratory catalog, and imports periodically this
			subset into its own application. Implementation guidance for this use case is provided
			in the <a href="labservices.html#LabServicesSearchRetrieve"><i>Searching and retrieving
					laboratory services</i></a> section of the specification.</li>
		<li>
			<b>Catalog administration using the FHIR API</b>: The laboratory maintains its
			compendium of services in a proprietary format, and delegates the standard publication
			of this compendium to an external organization operating an HL7 FHIR server of such
			catalogs. The application maintaining the laboratory compendium interacts with the FHIR
			server to keep the publication up to date, inserting, updating or retiring services
			into/from the FHIR catalog. Implementation guidance for this use case is provided in the
				<a href="labservices.html#LabServicesAdmin"><i>Administering laboratory
				services</i></a> section of the specification.</li>
		<li><b>Sharing a common semantic master catalog</b>: An organization exposes the set of
			standardized vocabularies needed to support full semantic interoperability for ordering
			and reporting laboratory services within a jurisdiction (e.g. a country). This reference
			set is represented as a generic catalog of all the laboratory services that are usable
			within the jurisdiction. This generic catalog is imported in whole or in parts by the
			applications of the ordering providers and of the laboratories of the jurisdiction.
			Implementation guidance for this use case is provided in the <a
				href="labservices.html#LabServicesSearchRetrieve"><i>Searching and retrieving
					laboratory services</i></a> section of the specification.</li>
		<li><b>Customized catalog shared in push mode</b>: The custodian of a laboratory catalog
			customizes its catalog for a particular group of consumers, and pushes this customized
			version to the information systems of each of these consumers. From that point, updates
			of this customized catalog are pushed to the same group of customers on a regular basis
			(for instance, weekly). Implementation guidance for this use case is provided in the <a
				href="interactions.html#PushInteractions"><i>Push interactions</i></a> section of
			the specification.</li>
	</ol>
</div>
