<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas-r5/fhir-single.xsd">
	<table class="note-to-balloters">
		<tbody>
			<tr><th><b>This page is excluded from the current ballot. The scope of the current ballot is limited to the &quot;laboratory service content&quot; of this IG.</b></th></tr>
		</tbody>
	</table>
	<br/>
	<p>This section lists the use cases for using libraries of order sets.</p>
	<ul>
		<li>A client of a content vendor’s system wishes to import the latest set of published order
			sets into its own catalog for deployment into its EHR.</li>
		<li>A content vendor wishes to import a collection of order sets from one of its client
			including all dependencies (e.g., orderable items mentioned in the order sets, order
			details, relevant order item constraints, etc…) into its own catalog.</li>
		<li>A health care provider wishes to sync its orderable item catalog and order set library
			with a content vendor. Any term added, updated, or inactivated should reflect
			immediately on the content vendor side. Also, the health care provider wishes to
			identify any catalog item that references an inactivated orderable item on the content
			vendor system in order to update the order set. </li>
		<li>A medication has been recalled. A content provider and a health care provider would like
			to identify all order sets that reference this recalled medication. The health care
			provider then wishes to sync its order set library with that of the content vendor’s and
			update all affected order sets based on vendor guidance prior to reimporting the updated
			order sets back into their own catalog. The updated order sets, are then deployed into
			the EHR.</li>
		<li>A health care organization with multiple facilities and hospitals maintains a master
			catalog of order sets. Each facility maintains its library of order sets and vocabulary
			derived from the master catalog but localized based on the facility’s needs and
			capabilities. Updates to the master catalog should be reflected at the individual
			facility/hospital level based on the governance practices of the facility and the parent
			organization.</li>
		<li>The client of a content vendor would like to import order sets ready for publication
			into their system. They search the catalog for all active order sets that are ready for
			publication and import that set into their local catalog. Once imported, an integrator
			reviews the order sets, makes the necessary changes, and deploys them to the EHR.</li>
	</ul>
</div>
